我想谈谈农场日和乐观的并发控制，
I'd like to like to talk about farms day
and optimistic concurrency control which
是主要有趣的技术，它利用了我们谈论农场的原因
is the main interesting technique that
uses the reason we're talking about farm
这是该系列中有关事务和复制的最后一篇文章，
it's this the last paper in the series
about transactions and replication and
分片，这仍然是一个开放的研究领域，人们完全可以
sharding and this is still an open
research area where people are totally
对绩效或绩效与一致性不满意
not satisfied with performance or in the
kind of performance versus consistency
可以进行权衡，他们仍在尝试做得更好
trade-offs that are available and
they're still trying to do better
特别是这份特殊的论文是由出色的表现所激发的
and in particular this particular paper
is motivated by the huge performance
这些新的RDMA NIC的潜力，所以您可能想知道，因为我们只是
potential of these new RDMA NICs
so you may be wondering since we just
阅读有关扳手的信息，农场与其他扳手有何不同
read about spanner
how farm differs some spanner both of
他们毕竟复制，他们使用两阶段提交的交易
them after all replicate and they use
two-phase commit for transactions of
在那个级别上，它们看起来就像是已部署系统中的扳手
that level they seem pretty similar
spanner as a is a deployed systems been
很长时间以来，它的主要重点是地理复制
used a lot for a long time its main
focus is on Geographic replication that
能够在东海岸和西海岸以及其他地方复制
is to be able to have copies on there
like east and west coasts and different
数据中心并能够进行合理有效的交易
data centers and be able to have
reasonably efficient transactions that
涉及许多不同地方的数据片段，最具创新性
involve pieces of data in lots of
different places and the most innovative
关于它的事情，因为为了尝试解决它多长时间的问题
thing about it because in order to try
to solve the problem of how long it
长距离进行两阶段提交是因为它有一个特殊的
takes to do two-phase commit over long
distances is that it has a special
使用同步时间和时间的只读事务的优化路径
optimization path for read-only
transactions using synchronized time and
如果记得，您会从扳手获得的性能是读/写
the performance you get out of spanner
if you remember is that a read/write
交易需要10到100毫秒，具体取决于
transaction takes 10 to 100 milliseconds
depending on how close together the
农场中不同的数据中心做出了非常不同的设计决策
different data centers are farm makes a
very different set of design decisions
并针对不同类型的工作负载首先是研究原型
and targets a different kind of workload
first of all it's a research prototype
因此它绝不是成品，而目标是探索
so it's not by any means a finished
product and the goal is to explore the
这些新的RDMA高速网络硬件的潜力，因此它实际上仍然
potential of these new RDMA high speed
networking hardware so it's really still
探索性系统，它假定所有副本都在同一个数据中心中
an exploratory system it assumes that
all replicas are in the same data center
绝对没有任何意义
absolutely it doesn't wouldn't make
sense
这些副本甚至位于不同的数据中心，更不用说在东海岸了
the replicas were in even in different
data centers let alone on East Coast
与西海岸之战，因此它并不是要解决扳手问题
versus West Coast so it's not trying to
solve a problem that spanner is about
如果整个数据中心宕机了怎么办，我能取出数据吗？
what happens if an entire data center
goes down can I so get out my data
确实，它具有容错能力的程度是针对个人的
really that's does the extent that it
has fault tolerance is for individual
崩溃，或者在整个数据中心断电并尝试恢复后尝试恢复
crashes or maybe try to recover after a
whole data center loses power and gets
再次恢复它使用这种RDMA技术，我将谈论但
restored again it uses this RDMA
technique which I'll talk about but
可能已经严重限制了设计选项，并且
already may turns out to seriously
restrict the design options and because
另一方面，该农场中的一部分被迫使用乐观并发控制
of this farm is forced to use optimistic
concurrency control on the other hand
他们获得的性能远远高于扳手农场所能做到的
the performance they get is far far
higher than spanner farm can do a
在58微秒内传输一个简单的事务，这来自图7
transit a simple transaction in 58
microseconds and this is from figure 7
和第6.3节，所以这是58微秒，而到10毫秒
and section 6.3 so this is 58
microseconds versus to 10 milliseconds
扳手所需的时间比扳手快一百倍，
that the spanner takes is that's about a
hundred times faster than spanner so
那也许是我们最大的巨大差异
that's maybe the main huge differences
that farm us how much higher performance
但不是针对地理复制的，所以您知道这个农场
but is not aimed at Geographic
replication so this you know farms
性能令人印象深刻，比其他任何东西都快
performance is extremely impressive like
how much faster than anything else
另一种看待方式是扳手和农场目标不同
another way to look at it is that
spanner and farm target different
瓶颈和跨度是人们担心的主要瓶颈
bottlenecks and span are the main
bottleneck the people worried about is
光速和网络光速之间的延迟和网络离开
the speed of light and network speed of
light delays and network leaves between
数据中心，而在农场中，设计担心的主要瓶颈
data centers whereas in farm the main
bottlenecks that the design is worried
大约是服务器上的CPU时间，因为他们希望
about is is CPU time on the server's
because they kind of wished away the
通过将所有副本置于同一位置来加快光速和网络延迟
speed of light and network delays by
putting all the replicas in the same
数据中心没事
data center all right
这样的背景如何使其适合684序列
so sort of the background of how this
fits into the 684 sequence the setup and
服务器场是您将它们全部运行在一个数据中心中，
farm is that you have it's all running
in one datacenter there's a sort of
配置管理器这是我们之前所见的配置
configuration manager this which we've
seen before and the configuration
经理决定哪个代表
managers in charge of deciding which rep
which
在每个数据分片之前，服务器应是备份中的主要服务器，如果
servers should be the primary in the
backup before each shard of data and if
您仔细阅读后会看到他们使用Zookeeper来帮助他们
you read carefully you'll see that they
use zookeeper in order to help them
实现此配置管理器，但这不是本文的重点
implement this configuration manager but
it's not not the focus of the paper at
所有相反，有趣的是，
all
instead the interesting thing is that
数据通过一堆主要备用付款人的密钥分片
the data is sharded split up by key
across a bunch of primary backup payers
所以我的意思是说一个分片继续存在，您知道主一台服务器主一台备份
so I mean one shard goes on you know
primary one server primary one backup
一个又一个短的主数据库来备份两个，依此类推，这意味着
one another short one primary to backup
two and so forth and that means that
每当您更新数据时，都需要在主数据库和
anytime you update data you need to
update it both on the primary and on the
备份，这些不是这些主副本，这些副本不由维护
backup and these are not these primaries
these replicas are not maintained by
PAC或类似的东西，而是更新所有数据副本
PACs or anything like it instead all the
replicas of the data are updated
每当有变化时，如果您阅读，则必须始终阅读
whenever there's a change and if you
read you always have to read from the
当然，这种复制的主要原因是容错和
primary the reason for this replication
of course is fault tolerance and the
他们得到的一种容错能力是，只要给定碎片的一个副本
kind of fault tolerance they get is that
as long as one replicas of a given shard
可用，那么该分片将可用，因此它们只需要一个
is available then that shard will be
available so they only require one
如果有数据的话，活的副本不是多数，也不是整个系统
living replica not a majority and the
system as a whole if there's say a data
中心白色电源故障，只要至少有一个，它就可以恢复
center white power failure it can
recover as long as there's at least one
系统中每个分片的副本的另一种放置方式是
replicas of every shard in the system
another way of putting that is if you
他们有F加一个副本，那么他们可以忍受F次失败
they have F plus one replicas then they
can tolerate up to F failures for that
碎片，除了每种数据的主要备份副本外，
shard in addition to the primary backup
copies of each sort of data there's
运行它的事务代码可能是最方便的
transaction code that runs it's maybe
most convenient to think of the
交易代码作为独立的客户端运行，实际上它们在运行交易
transaction code is running as separate
clients in fact they run the transaction
在与实际服务器场存储相同的机器上进行实验的代码
code in their experiments on the same
machines as the actual farm storage
服务器，但我通常会认为它们是一组单独的客户端，
servers but I'll mostly think of them as
as being a separate set of clients and
客户端正在运行事务，并且该事务需要读写
the clients are running transactions and
the transactions need to read and write
除这些外，还存储在分片服务器中的数据对象
data objects that are stored in the
in the sharded servers in addition these
交易这些客户每个客户不仅运行交易，而且还运行
transaction these clients each client
not only runs the transactions but also
充当两阶段提交的事务协调器
acts as that transaction coordinator for
two-phase commit
好吧，这是他们获得性能的基本方法，因为这真的
okay so it's the basic set up the way
they get performance because this really
这是一篇有关如何获得高性能并仍然拥有
this is a paper all about how you can
get high performance and still have
通过分片获得高性能的一种方式是
transactions one way they get high
performances with sharding these are the
从某种意义上讲，主要成分是通过在实验中分片
ingredients in a sense the main way is
through sharding in experiments they
通过90种方式将其数据分摊到90台服务器上，也许是45种方式，而不是
shard their data over 90 ways for 90
servers or maybe it's 45 ways and not
只要操作和不同的碎片差不多
just if as long as the operations and
different shards are more or less
彼此独立，可自动为您加速90倍
independent of each other that just gets
you an automatic 90 times speed up
因为您可以运行90糖浆中的任何糖浆
because you can run whatever it is
you're running in parallel on 90 syrups
这个巨大的钱来自较短的分片，还有他们为了获得的另一个技巧
this huge went from shorter sharding um
another trick they play in order to get
良好的性能，因为所有数据都必须容纳在它们不需要的服务器的RAM中
good performance as the data all has to
fit in the RAM of the servers they don't
真正将数据存储在磁盘上，所有这些都必须放入RAM中，这意味着
really store the data on disk
it all has to fit in RAM and that means
当然，您可以很快摆脱另一种方式，即它们变得很高
of course you can get out of pretty
quickly another way that they get high
性能是他们需要容忍掉电，这意味着他们
performance is they need to tolerate
power failures which means that they
不能只是使用RAM，因为它们需要在上电后恢复数据
can't just be using RAM because they
need to recover the data after a power
发生故障，RAM在断电时会丢失内容，因此它们有一个聪明的选择
failure and RAM loses contents on a
power failure so they have a clever
非易失性Ram方案，用于让RAM的内容在电源中存活
non-volatile Ram scheme for having the
contents of RAM the data survived power
失败，这与将数据持久存储在磁盘上相反
failures this is in contrast to storing
the data persistently on disk i'm is
比磁盘快得多他们使用的另一个技巧是使用此RDMA
much faster than disk um another trick
they play is they use this RDMA
实质上是聪明的网络接口卡技术
technique which essentially clever
network interface cards that allow that
接受指示我们直接进入接口卡的数据包
accept packets that instruct that then
that we're interface card to directly
读写服务器的内存，而不会中断服务器
read and write the memory of the server
without interrupting the server I know
他们玩的技巧就是您通常所说的内核旁路
that trick they play is what you often
call kernel bypass
这意味着应用程序级代码可以直接访问网络
which means that the application level
code can directly access the network
接口卡，而无需涉及内核，所以这些都是
interface card without getting the
kernel involved okay so these are all
我们正在寻找的那种巧妙的技巧倒掉了
the sort of clever tricks we're looking
at out pour it that they used to get
高性能，我将谈论我们已经讨论过分片
high performance and I'll talk about
we've already talked about sharding a
很多，但我将在本讲座中讨论其余内容
lot but I'll talk about the rest in this
lecture
好吧，首先我要谈谈非易失性Ram，这是真的
okay so first I'll talk about
non-volatile Ram I mean this is really a
不会真正影响设计其余部分的话题
topic that doesn't doesn't really affect
the rest of the design directly as I
当客户端更新时，所有数据和用于场的数据都存储在RAM中
said all the data and for farm is stored
in RAM when you update it when a client
交易更新了一条数据，这实际上意味着它可以到达
transaction updates a piece of data what
that really means is it reaches out to
存储数据并导致这些服务器修改
the relevant servers that store the data
and causes those servers to modify the
事务正在修改的任何对象都可以在对象中对其进行修改
whatever object is the transaction is
modifying to object modify it right in
RAM，就写入而言，它们不会进入磁盘，这就是您
RAM and that's as far as the writes get
they don't go to disk and this is you
知道与您的筏实施的对比，例如花了多少钱
know contrast to your raft
implementations for example which spent
很多时间将数据持久保存到磁盘上没有持久性，在服务器场中
a lot of time persisting data to disk
there's no persisting and in farm this
在RAM中写东西是一件大事，写ram大约需要200
is a big wind writing stuff in RAM write
a write to ram takes about 200
十亿分之一秒，而对固态硬盘的袭击甚至是非常快的
nanoseconds whereas a raid even to a
solid state drive which is pretty fast a
失速寻道驱动器的权利大约需要一百微秒，然后写入
right to a stall seek drive takes about
a hundred microseconds and a write to
我们的硬盘驱动器大约需要十毫秒，因此能够写入
our hard drive takes about ten
milliseconds so being able to write to
ram值得许多数量级和速度的交易
ram is worth many many orders of
magnitude and speed for transactions
会改变事物，但伊朗当然会丢失其内容和电源故障，因此
that modify things but of course iran
loses its content and a power failure so
它本身并不是持久的，您可能会认为写作
it's not persistent by itself as a side
you might think that writing
如果您有副本服务器，则对多个服务器的RAM进行修改
modifications to the RAM of multiple
servers that if you have replica servers
然后您更新所有可能具有足够持久性的副本，因此
and you update all the replicas that
that might be persistent enough and so
毕竟，如果您有F 1 F +1个副本，则最多可以容忍F个故障，并且
after all if you have F 1 F +1 replicas
you can tolerate up to F failures and
仅在多个服务器上写入Ram的原因不好
the reason why just simply writing to
Ram on multiple servers is not good
一个站点范围内的电源故障将足以破坏
enough is that a site-wide power failure
will destroy
您所有的服务器，从而违反了故障发生的假设
all of your servers and thus violating
the assumption that the failures are in
不同的服务器是独立的，所以我们需要一个即使它也可以工作的方案
different servers are independent so we
need a scheme that it's gonna work even
如果整个数据中心的电源故障，那么论坛会做什么呢？
if power fails to the entire data center
so what what forum does is it it puts a
为每个机架中的一块大电池供电，并通过
battery a big battery in every rack and
runs the power supply system through the
电池，因此如果发生电源故障，电池会自动接管电池，
batteries so the batteries automatically
take over if there's a power failure and
保持所有机器运行至少到电池出现故障为止，但是当然
keep all their machines running at least
until the battery fails but of course
你知道电池不是很大，可能只能用自己的电池
you know the battery is not very big it
may only be able to run their their
机器说了10分钟之类的时间，因此电池本身不足
machines for say 10 minutes or something
so the battery by itself is not enough
为了使系统能够承受较长的电源故障，因此
to make this the system be able to
withstand a lengthy power failure so
而是当电池系统看到主电源出现故障时，
instead the battery system when it sees
that the main power is failed the
电池系统在保持服务器的Marling的同时也会提醒
battery system while it keeps the
server's Marling also alerts the
服务器的所有服务器，并带有某种中断或消息告诉
server's all the servers and with some
kind of interrupt or message telling
他们看起来力量刚刚失败，您知道您只剩10分钟了
them look the powers just failed you
know you only got 10 minutes left before
电池也会发生故障，因此此时场服务器上的软件会复制所有
the batteries fail also so at that point
the software on farms servers copies all
的雨水活动会先停止对农场的所有处理，然后再复制每个
of rain active stops all processing it
for farm first and then copies each
服务器将其所有RAM复制到与之相连的固态驱动器
server copies all of its RAM to a
solid-state drive attached to that
服务器是我所希望的，可能需要几分钟，而一旦所有的RAM被
server I'm what wished could take a
couple minutes and once all the RAM is
复制到固态驱动器，然后机器自行关闭并转动
copied to the solid-state drive then the
machine shuts itself down and turns
本身关闭，所以如果一切顺利，所有机器都将发生站点范围的电源故障
itself off so if all goes well there's a
site-wide power failure all the machines
当数据中心恢复供电时，将其RAM保存到磁盘
save their RAM to disk when the power
comes back up in the datacenter all the
机器重启时将读取保存在磁盘上的内存映像
machines will when they reboot will read
the memory image that was saved on disk
恢复到RAM中，但必须进行一些恢复，但基本上
restored into RAM and but there's some
recovery that has to go on but basically
他们不会因为力量而失去任何持久状态
they won't have lost any of their
persistent state due to the power
失败，这实际上意味着该农场正在使用常规Ram
failure and so what that really means is
that the farm is using conventional Ram
但本质上使RAM非易失性能够承受电源
but it's essentially made the RAM
non-volatile being able to survive power
使用这种电池的技巧而导致故障
failures with the
this trick of using a battery having a
电池警报服务器使服务器固态存储RAM内容
battery alert the server having the
server store the RAM content solid-state
驱动有关nvram方案的任何问题，这是一个有用的
drives any questions about the nvram
scheme alright this is a is a useful
技巧，但值得记住的是，它只有在有
trick but it is worthwhile keeping mind
that it really only helps if there's
停电就是如果您只知道整个事件序列，
power failures that is if the you know
the whole sequence of events only it
如果电池发现主电源出现故障，则将其设置为火车
gets set in train when the battery
notices that the main power is failed if
还有其他导致服务器故障的原因，例如
there's some other reason
causing the server to fail like
硬件出现问题或软件中存在错误
something goes wrong with the hardware
or there's a bug in the software that
导致崩溃那些崩溃非易失性Ram系统只是一无所有
causes a crash those crashes the
non-volatile Ram system is just nothing
与这些崩溃有关的那些崩溃将导致计算机重新启动并
to do with those crashes those crashes
will cause the machine to reboot and
丢失其RAM中的内容，它将无法恢复它们，因此
lose the contents of its RAM and it
won't be able to recover them so this
NVRAM方案适用于电源故障，但不适用于其他崩溃，所以这就是为什么
NVRAM scheme is good for power failures
but not other crashes and so that's why
除了NVRAM场外，还具有多个副本的多个副本
in addition to the NVRAM farm also has
multiple copies multiple replicas of
每个分片都可以，因此该NVRAM方案从根本上消除了
each shard all right so this NVRAM
scheme essentially eliminates
持久性成为系统性能的瓶颈
persistence rates as a bottleneck in the
performance of the system leaving only
当性能瓶颈在网络和CPU上时，这就是我们要讲的
as performance bottlenecks the network
and the CPU which is what we'll talk
关于下一个确定，所以有一个问题，即数据中心电源是否发生故障并且场丢失
about next ok so there's a question if
the datacenter power fails and farm lose
固态硬盘的所有内容都可以将所有数据传送到
everything for solid-state drive would
it be possible to carry all the data to
一个不同的数据中心并原则上绝对在那里继续运行
a different data center and continue
operation there in principle absolutely
在实践中，我认为恢复电源肯定会更容易
in practice I think would be would all
certainly be easier to restore power to
数据中心然后移动驱动器，问题是没有电源，并且
the data center then to move the drives
the problem is there's no power and the
老式旧数据中心的电源，因此您必须物理移动驱动器
power in the dated old data center so
you'd have to physically move the drives
而计算机可能只是新数据中心的驱动器，所以这是
and the computers maybe just the drives
to the new data center so this was if
您想这样做，这可能是可行的，但肯定不是
you wanted to do this it might be
possible but it's certainly not
这不是农场设计师所想的，他们认为电源已恢复
it's not what the farm designers had in
mind they assumed the power be restored
好的，那是NVRAM，在这一点上，我们可以忽略其余的nvram
okay so that's NVRAM and at this point
we can just ignore nvram for the rest of
并非如此，它并不会真正与其余的设计交互
the design it doesn't it doesn't really
interact with the rest of the design
除了我们知道必须担心将数据写入磁盘之外，所以
except that we know we're have to worry
about writing data to disk all right so
正如我提到的，一旦您消除拥有大量数据，剩下的瓶颈
as I mentioned the remaining bottlenecks
once you eliminate having a great data
保留在磁盘上以保持剩余瓶颈与CPU和
to disk for persistence in remaining
bottlenecks have to do with the CPU and
实际上是Farman的网络，实际上是我曾经使用过的许多系统
the network in fact in farman and indeed
a lot of the systems that i've been
与一个巨大的瓶颈有关的是要处理的CPU时间
involved with the a huge bottleneck has
been the cpu time required to deal with
网络互动，因此现在我们可以将CPU视为此处的共同瓶颈
network interactions so now we're can
CPU are kind of joint bottlenecks here
场没有任何类型的光网络速度问题，它只有
farm doesn't have any kind of speed of
light network problems it just has the
问题，或者只是花费大量时间来消除瓶颈
problems or it just spends a lot of time
eliminating bottlenecks having to do is
将网络数据传入和传出计算机，因此首先作为背景
getting network data into and out of the
computers so first as a background I
想要列出传统架构的用途，例如
want to lay out what the conventional
architecture is for getting things like
应用程序之间和不同计算机上的远程过程调用数据包
remote procedure call packets between
applications and on different computers
这样我们就可以了解为什么农场采用的这种方法更多
just so that can we have an idea of why
this approach that farm takes is more
高效，所以通常情况是在一台可能要
efficient so typically what's going on
is on one computer that maybe wants to
发送一个过程调用消息，您可能有一个应用程序，然后
send a procedure call message you might
have an application and then the
应用程序在用户空间中运行，这里有一个用户内核边界
application is running in user space
there's a user kernel boundary here the
应用程序对内核进行系统调用，这并不是特别便宜
application makes system calls into the
kernel which are not particularly cheap
为了发送数据，然后在
所涉及的内核正在通过网络发送数据，通常可能是
kernel involved is sending data over the
network there might be what's usually
称为套接字层，可进行缓冲，其中涉及复制
called a socket layer that does
buffering which involves copying the
数据需要时间，通常会有一个复杂的TCP
data which takes time there's typically
a complex TCP
协议栈，它了解所有有关重传和顺序的信息
the protocol stack that knows all about
things like retransmitting and sequence
数字，校验和和流控制那里有很多处理
numbers and check sums and flow control
there's quite a bit of processing there
底部有一块称为网络接口的硬件
at the bottom there's a piece of
hardware called the network interface
带有一堆寄存器的卡，内核可以通过该寄存器进行配置
card which is has a bunch of registers
that the kernel can talk to to configure
它并且它具有通过电缆将位发送到网络上所需的硬件
it and it has hardware required to send
bits out over the cable onto the network
内核中有某种网络接口卡驱动程序，
and so there's some sort of network
interface card driver in the kernel and
然后所有我们认为价格卡的自我尊重都使用直接记忆
then all self respecting that we're
gonna price cards use direct memory
可以将数据包移入和移出主机内存，因此
access to move packets into and out of
host memory so there's going to be
网络接口卡D做成的数据包队列之类的东西
things like queues of packets that the
network interfaces card has D made into
存储等待内核读取和传出的色相的数据包
memory the waiting for the kernel to
read and outgoing hues the packets that
内核希望我们尽快面对面发送
the kernel would like then that we're
going to face to car to send as soon as
方便吧，所以您想发送类似RPC请求的消息，让我们开始吧
convenient all right so you want to send
a message like an RPC request let's go
从应用程序通过堆栈网络接口卡向下发送
down from the application through the
stack network interface card sends the
放在电缆上然后在另一侧没有反向堆叠
bits out on a cable and then there's the
reverse stack on the other side isn't
网络接口硬件在内核中，然后器官或面部可能
network interface Hardware here in the
kernel then organ or face might
中断内核内核运行驱动程序代码，该程序将数据包传递给TCP
interrupt the kernel kernel runs driver
Code which hands packets to the TCP
协议，将它们写入缓冲区，等待应用程序读取它们
protocol which writes them into buffers
waiting for the application to read them
在某个时刻，应用程序四处读取它们，从而进行系统调用
at some point the application gets
around reading them makes system calls
进入内核，将这些缓冲区中的数据复制到用户空间，这是一个
into the kernel copies the data out of
these buffers into user space this is a
很多软件，很多处理，很多昂贵的CPU
lot of software it's a lot of processing
and a lot of fairly expensive CPU
系统调用和中断等操作以及结果复制数据
operations like system calls and
interrupts and copying data as a result
因此，传统的网络通信相对较慢，因此很难构建
so classical Network communication is
relatively slow it's quite hard to build
具有传统架构的RPC系统
an RPC system with the kind of
traditional architecture that can
每秒传递超过数十万或BC消息
deliver more than say a few hundred
thousand or BC messages per second and
可能看起来很多，但数量级太少了
that might seem like a lot but it's
orders of magnitude too few for the kind
场试图达到的性能指标
of performance that farm is trying to
target and in general that
每秒十万个PC远远不及速度
couple hundred thousand our pcs per
second is far far less than the speed
网络接口中的实际网络硬件（如网络线）
that the actual network hardware like
Network wire in the network interface
卡通常能够将这些电缆以10吉比特的速度运行
card is capable of typically these
cables run at things like 10 gigabits
每秒很难编写我们的PC软件
per second it's very very hard to write
our PC software that can generate small
数据库经常需要使用的那种消息，很难
messages of the kind that databases
often need to use it's very hard to
以这种风格编写可以生成或吸收10之类的软件的软件
write software in this style that can
generate or absorb anything like 10
每秒的千兆字节消息数百万甚至数千万
gigabits per second of messages that's
millions maybe tens of millions of
每秒的邮件数量还可以，因此这是服务器场不使用的计划，
messages per second ok so this is the
plan that farm doesn't use and a sort of
对此计划的反应是农场使用--降低生产成本的想法
a reaction to to this plan instead farm
uses - - ideas to reduce the costs of
围绕第一个推送数据包，我将其称为内核旁路和
pushing packets around the first one
I'll call kernel bypass and the idea
这里是，而不是应用程序通过
here is that instead of the application
sending all its data down through a
复杂的内核代码堆栈，而不是内核配置的应用程序
complex stack of kernel code instead the
application the kernel configures the
计算机中的保护机制，以允许应用程序直接访问
protection machinery in the computer to
allow the application direct access to
网络接口卡，因此应用程序实际上可以与
network interface card so the
application can actually reach out and
触摸网络接口寄存器，并告诉它该怎么做
touch the network interfaces registers
and tell it what to do in addition the
网络接口卡，当它是DMA且该内核旁路方案是它的DNA
network interface card when it DMAs
and this kernel bypass scheme it DNA's
直接进入应用程序内存，应用程序可以在其中看到字节
directly into application memory where
the application can see the bytes
在没有内核干预的情况下以及应用程序何时直接到达
arriving directly without kernel
intervention and when the application
需要发送数据的应用程序可以创建网络接口的队列
needs to send data the application can
create queues that the network interface
卡可以直接通过DMA读取并通过电线发送，所以现在我们已经
card can directly read with DMA and send
out over the wire so now we've
完全消除了网络内核中涉及的所有内核代码
completely eliminated all the kernel
code involved in networking kernels just
不参与，没有系统调用，没有中断
not involved there's no system calls
there's no interrupts
该应用程序只是直接说明为什么网络接口是它的内存
the application just directly reason why
it's memory that the network interface
卡看到另一边当然是同一个东西，这是这个
card sees and of course the same thing
on the other side and this is a this is
网络上实际上不可能实现的想法
an idea that is actually was not
possible years ago with network
接口卡，但可以设置大多数现代的严肃网络接口卡
interface cards but most modern serious
network interface cards okay can be set
为此，它确实需要您知道的应用程序
up to do this it does however require
that the application you know you know
TCP为您执行的所有操作，例如校验和或重新传输
all those things that TCP was doing for
you like check sums or retransmission
现在，如果我们要执行此操作，则该应用程序将由您负责
the application would now be in charge
if we wanted to do this you can actually
使用您可以在升级过程中找到的工具包自己进行内核绕过
do this yourself kernel bypass using a
toolkit that you can find on the way up
称为DP DK，使用起来相对容易
called
DP DK and it's relatively easy to use
并允许人们编写超高性能的网络应用程序
and allows people to write extremely
high performance networking applications
但是，因此表单确实会使用它，因此您直接与
but and so so form does use this it's
applications directly you talk to the
将DM ace颈项并入应用程序存储器中，我们有一个学生
neck the neck DM ace things right into
application memory we have a student
问题，对不起，这是否意味着农场计算机运行了修改过的
question I'm sorry yes does this mean
that farm machines run a modified
操作系统II我不知道我相信这个问题的实际答案
operating system well I I don't know the
actual answer that question I believe
服务器场是在Windows上运行的某种形式的Windows，无论是否必须
farm is runs on Windows some form of
Windows whether or not they had to
修改Windows我不知道在Linux世界中，在Linux世界中
modify Windows I do not know in the sort
of Linux world in Linux world there's
已经对此提供了完全支持，它确实需要内核干预
already full support for this
it does require kernel intervention
因为内核必须愿意提供通常的应用程序代码
because the kernel has to be willing to
give ordinarily application code cannot
直接对设备执行任何操作，因此必须修改Linux以允许
do anything directly with devices so
Linux has had to be modified to allow
允许内核将硬件访问权委派给应用程序，因此
the allow the kernel to delegate
hardware access to applications so it
确实需要修改内核，那些监视场合已经在Linux中
does require kernel modifications those
monitor occasions are already in Linux
而且也许在Windows中也已经
and maybe already in Windows also in
addition though this
在相当聪明的尼克斯上，因为您当然要拥有多个
on fairly intelligent Knicks because of
course you're going to have multiple
想要通过网络接口卡玩此游戏的应用程序等
applications that want to play this game
with a network interface card and so
现代的NIC实际上知道如何与多个不同的线索对话，因此您
modern NICs actually know about talking
to multiple distinct cues so that you
可以有多个应用程序，每个应用程序都有自己的线索和尼克
can have multiple applications each with
its own set of cues and the the Nick
知道所以它确实需要修改很多东西好吗
knows about so it did it has required
modification of a lot of things okay
所以第一步是上校绕过的想法第二步甚至更聪明
so sort of step one is is Colonel bypass
idea step two is even cleverer next and
现在我们开始进入目前尚未广泛使用的硬件
now we're starting to get into hardware
that is not in wide use of the moment
您可以从商业上购买它，但是默认情况下不是该RDMA方案
you can buy it commercially but it's not
the default is this RDMA scheme which is
远程直接内存访问，这是一种特殊的网络
remote direct memory access and here
this is sort of special kind of network
支持远程的接口卡支持我们的DMA，因此现在我们有了RDM
interface cards that support remote
support our DMA so now we have an RDM a
脖子两边都要这些
neck both sides have to have these
特殊的网络接口卡，所以我在画这些是通过电缆连接的
special network interface cards so I'm
drawing these is connected by a cable in
事实上，这里总是有一个开关，可以连接许多不同的
fact always there's a switch here that
has connections to many different
服务器，并允许任何服务器与任何服务器对话，所以我们有这些RDMA
servers and allows any server to talk to
any server okay so we have these RDMA
脖子，我们再次得到了应用程序和应用程序协助
necks and we had again we have the
applications and application assist
内存，尽管应用程序实际上可以发送一条特殊消息
memory and now though the application
can essentially send a special message
通过询问，所以我们在源主机上有一个应用程序
through the neck that asks so we have a
an application on the source host and
也许我们不会将其称为目标主机可以发送特殊
maybe we wouldn't call this the
destination host can send a special
消息通过我们的DMA系统通知该网络接口卡
message through the our DMA system that
tells this network interface card to
直接读取或写入一个字节的内存，可能是一个缓存行
directly read or write a byte some bytes
of memory probably a cache line of
目标应用程序地址空间中的内存
memory in
the target applications address space
直接，因此网络接口控制器上的硬件和软件正在执行
directly so hardware and software on the
network interface controller are doing a
读取和写入读取或写入应用程序目标应用程序内存
read and write read or write of the
application target applications memory
直接，然后我们在这里进行了某种请求，导致读取
directly and then so we have a sort of
request going here that causes the read
或写入，然后将结果发送回另外两个传入队列
or write and then sending the result
back to really two other incoming queue
在源应用程序上，与此有关的很酷的事情是，这台计算机的
on the source application and the cool
thing about this is that this computer's
该应用程序的CPU对读取或写入数据一无所知
the CPU this application didn't know
anything about the read or write the
读取或写入完全在网络接口卡的固件中执行
read or write is executed completely in
firmware in the network interface card
因此它不是没有中断，应用程序不必考虑
so it's not there's no interrupts here
the application didn't have to think
关于请求或仅考虑答复网络接口卡
about the request or think about
replying network interface card just
读取或写入内存，并将结果发送回源应用程序
reads or writes a memory and sends a
result back to the source application
而这是您所需要做的所有事情中低得多的开销方法
and this is much much lower overhead way
of getting at of all you need to do is
读取或写入目标应用程序RAM中的内存和东西，这是一个
read or write memory and stuff in the
RAM of the target application this is a
简单的读写方式比发送PC呼叫快得多
much faster way of doing a simple read
or write than sending in our PC call
即使使用魔术内核绕过网络，这还是一个问题，这是否意味着
even with magic kernel bypass networking
it's a question does this mean that
可能一直需要内核绕过才能完全起作用，您知道我不知道
already may always require kernel bypass
to work at all you know I don't know the
对此的回答我想我只听说过它与内核结合使用
answer to that I think I've only ever
heard it used in conjunction with kernel
绕过库兹，你知道对这一切感兴趣的人或
bypass cuz you know the people who are
interested in any of this or are
对它感兴趣只是为了获得出色的性能，我认为您会浪费
interested in it only for tremendous
performance and I think you would waste
你丢了很多表演，我猜你丢了很多
you throw away a lot of the performance
I'm guessing you throw away a lot of the
如果您必须通过内核发送请求，则可以提高性能
performance win if you had to send the
requests through the kernel okay another
问题记录TCP软件的TCP支持顺序的问题
question that the the question notes
TCP software's TCP supports in order
交付重复检测以及许多其他出色的性能
delivery duplicate detection and a lot
of other excellent properties which you
实际需要，因此如果此设置实际上将非常尴尬
actually need and so it would actually
be extremely awkward if this setup
牺牲了可靠的交货或按订单交货等等答案
sacrificed reliable delivery or in order
delivery and so the answer the question
实际上，这些是DMA NIC运行它们自己可靠的顺序协议，
is actually these are DMA NICs run their
own reliable sequenced protocol that's
像TCP，虽然不是脖子之间的TCP，所以当您询问已经
like TCP although not TCP between the
necks and so when you ask your already
是阅读或书写的脖子，它将使您保持传输状态，直到您
am a neck to do a read or write it'll
keep you transmitting until if the you
知道请求是否丢失，并保证意思直到它得到
know if the request is lost and keep
reassurance meaning till it gets a
响应，它实际上告诉原始软件做了请求
response and it actually tells the
originating software did the request
成功与否，所以您最终会得到认可，是的，您
succeed or not so you get an
acknowledgment back finally so yeah you
知道实际上必须牺牲大多数TCP是好的属性
know in fact have to sacrifice
most of TCP is good properties now this
东西只能在本地网络上工作，我不相信我们的DMA是
stuff only works over a local network I
don't believe our DMA would be
令人满意，就像在遥远的数据中心之间，所以所有这些都需要进行调整
satisfactory like between distant data
centers so there's all tuned up for very
低速的光线访问，可以说是
low speed of light access okay a
particular piece of jargon that the
纸张使用是我们DMA的一方面，而这基本上就是我刚刚
paper uses is one-sided our DMA and
that's basically what I've just
当应用程序使用我们的DMA读取或写入另一个的内存时提到
mentioned when application uses our DMA
to read or write the memory of another
那是我们DMA现在的一个站点，事实上，服务器场使用DMA在RPC中发送消息
that's one site our DMA now in fact farm
uses our DMA to send messages in an RPC
像协议，因此实际上有时场直接读取我们DMA的一面
like protocol so in fact sometimes farm
directly reads with one sided our DMA
但有时场使用我们的DMA的目的是将一条消息附加到
but sometimes what farm is using our DMA
for is to append a message to an
目标内部的传入消息队列，因此有时
incoming message queue inside the target
so sometimes what the what the
很好，实际上总是在写，而场实际上正在使用我们的DMA
well actually always with writes what
farm is actually doing is using our DMA
编写以将新消息附加到目标中的传入队列中
to write to append a new message to an
incoming queue in the target which the
目标将拉动，因为这里没有人会打断目标
target will pull since there's nobody
interrupts here the way target
这样的消息的目的地知道我收到的消息的方式
the way the destination of a message
like this knows I got the messages that
定期检查这些键队列和内存之一，以查看我如何
periodically checks one of these keys
queues and memory to see how have I
收到任何人的最新消息，好吧，一旦我做完，MA只是为了
gotten a recent message from anyone
okay so once I did already MA is just to
读取或写入，但使用DMA发送消息或将消息追加到消息后
read or write but using our DMA to send
a message or append either to a message
队列或日志，有时场会附加消息或日志
queue or to a log
sometimes farm appends messages or log
日志和另一台服务器上的条目也使用我们的DMA，您知道此内存
entries to a log and another server also
uses our DMA and you know this memory
被写入的都是非易失性的，因此所有消息
that's being written into is all
non-volatile so all of it the message
如果发生电源故障，则将所有数据排队写入磁盘
queues it's all written to disk if
there's a power failure the performance
图2显示了您可以减少DMA读取的一千万次
of this is the figure 2 shows that you
can get 10 million small our DMA reads
并每秒写入，这比您发送的速度快得多
and writes per second which is fantastic
far far faster than you can send
消息，例如使用TCP的计算机以及使用DMA执行简单操作的延迟
messages like our pcs using TCP and the
latency of using our DMA to do a simple
读或写大约是5微秒，所以这又很短5
read or write is about 5 microseconds so
again this is you know very very short 5
微秒，这比访问您自己的本地内存要慢，但是
microseconds is it's slower than
accessing your own local memory but it's
比人们在网络中做的其他任何事情都快，所以这有点像
faster than sort of anything else people
do in networks ok so this is sort of a
承诺不久前就会出现这种神话般的DMA技术
promise there's this fabulous our DMA
technology that came out a while ago
人们在农场要剥削，你知道最酷的可能
that at the farm people wanted to
exploit you know the coolest possible
您可以想象的事情是使用我们的DMA一个符号
thing that you could imagine doing with
this is using our DMA one sign it
直接拥有所有理由已经是理由权利
already am a reason rights to directly
do all the reason writes a records
存储在数据库服务器内存中，所以如果我们能够
stored in database servers memory so
wouldn't be fantastic if we could just
从不与数据库服务器CPU或软件对话，而只是获取那些
never talk to the database server CPU or
software but just get at the data that
我们需要您在5微秒内使用直接单侧DMA弹出
we need you know in five microseconds a
pop using direct one-sided our DMA
Reiser写道，从某种意义上说，本文是关于您的，您知道您从那里开始
Reiser writes so in a sense this paper
is about you know you you start there
您实际上需要做什么才能构建有用的东西
what do you have to do to actually build
something useful so an interesting
顺便问一下，您实际上可以实施交易吗
question by the way is could you in fact
implement transactions
使用单面RDMA，您知道我们想要读取或写入数据的任何信息
using one-sided RDMA that is you know
anything we wanted to read or write data
在服务器中，唯一的用途可能是而且永远不会实际发送具有以下内容的消息
in server the only use already may and
never actually send messages that have
由服务器软件解释是值得考虑的
to be interpreted by the server software
it's worth thinking about
从某种意义上说，农场正在用否回答该问题，因为那不是
in a sense farm is answering that
question with a no because that's not
农场的运作方式确实如此，但绝对值得思考
really how farm works but but it is
absolutely worth thinking how come
纯粹的单面RDMA无法正常工作，因此使用方面的挑战
pure one-sided RDMA couldn't be made to
work alright so the challenges to using
具有复制和分片功能的事务系统中的DMA
our DMA in a transactional system that
has replication and sharding so that
那就是我们面临的挑战是如何结合已经完成的交易
that's the challenge we have is how to
combine already made with transactions
图表和复制，因为您需要分片和事务
charting and replication because you
need to have sharding and transactions
复制以拥有非常有用的数据库系统，事实证明，所有
replication to have a seriously useful
database system it turns out that all
到目前为止，我们进行交易复制所需的协议
the protocols we've seen so far for
doing transactions replication require
服务器必须积极参与服务器软件的参与
active participation by the server
software that is the server has to be in
到目前为止，我们已经看到的所有协议服务器都在积极参与帮助
客户端可以读取或写入数据，例如在两阶段中
the clients get at read or write the
data so for example in the two-phase
提交方案，我们已经看到服务器必须做一些事情，例如决定是否
commit schemes we've seen the server has
to do things like decide whether a
记录被锁定，如果它不能走，则将其设置在正确的位置上，这是不清楚的
record is locked and if it's not walk
set the lock on it right it's not clear
您如何使用我们的DMA来做到这一点，服务器必须执行扳手中的操作
how you could do that with our DMA the
server has to do things like in spanner
您知道所有这些版本都是服务器在考虑的
you know there's all these versions it
was the server that was thinking about
如果我们分两阶段进行交易，如何类似地查找最新版本
在服务器上提交数据不仅仅是数据
commit
data on the server it's not just data
有已提交的数据有已写入但尚未提交的数据
there's committed data there's data
that's been written but hasn't committed
传统上，一遍又一遍地是服务器来确定数据是否
yet and again traditionally it's the
server that sorts out whether data
最近提交的数据已经提交，这是为了保护
recently updated data is committed yet
and that's to sort of protect the
您知道的客户阻止他们查看已锁定或尚未锁定的数据
clients from you know prevent them from
seeing data that's locked or not yet
知道是坚定的，这意味着没有聪明
known to be committed and what that
means is that without some clever
认为RDMA或单方面使用我们的DME
thought
RDMA or one-sided pure use of our DME
单面RDMA似乎并不立即与事务兼容
one-sided RDMA doesn't seem to be
immediately compatible with transactions
和复制，甚至是服务器场，而服务器场确实使用单面读取来获取
and replication and indeed farm while
farm does use one-sided it reads to get
直接从数据库中的数据中删除它不能使用单面权限
out directly at data in the database it
is not not able to use one-sided rights
修改数据还可以，所以这使我们可以乐观地控制并发
to modify the data okay so this leads us
to optimistic concurrency control it
事实证明，从某种意义上说，主要技巧是服务器场用来允许它们都使用RDMA
turns out that the main trick in a sense
that farm uses to allow it both use RDMA
并通过使用乐观并发控制来获得交易，因此，如果您
and get transactions is by using
optimistic concurrency control so if you
还记得我之前提到的并发控制方案
remember I mentioned earlier that
concurrency control schemes are kind of
分为两大类
divided into two broad categories
悲观和乐观悲观方案使用锁，其想法是
pessimistic and optimistic pessimistic
schemes use locks and the idea is that
如果您有一笔交易要先读取或写入一些数据
if you have a transaction that's gonna
read or write some data before you can
读取或写入数据或完全查看它必须获得一个锁并且必须
read or write the data or look at it at
all it must acquire a lock and it must
等待锁定，因此您了解了例如两阶段锁定
wait for the lock and so you read about
two-phase locking for example in that
从633读取数据，因此在使用数据之前，必须先锁定数据并按住
reading from 633 so before you use data
you have to lock it and you hold the
锁定整个交易期间，并且仅在交易
lock for the entire duration of the
transaction and only if the transaction
提交或中止您是否释放锁，并且是否存在冲突，因为
commits or aborts do you release the
lock and if there's conflicts because
两个事务想要同时写入相同的数据，或者一个事务想要
two transactions want to write the same
data at the same time or one wants to
阅读，一个怪物正确，他们不能同时做到其中之一
read and one that monster right they
can't do it at the same time one of them
必须阻止或除向您发送一些数据的交易以外的所有交易
has to block or all but one of the
transactions that went to you some data
错过了一个等待释放锁的块，当然，这个锁
missed a block wait for the lock to be
released um and of course this locking
方案是必须锁定数据并且必须有人保留的事实
scheme is the fact that the data has to
be locked and that somebody has to keep
跟踪谁拥有锁以及何时释放锁等
track of who owns the lock and when the
lock is released etcetera
这是使我们的DMA产生一件事的原因，目前尚不清楚如何进行版权保护或
this is one thing that makes our DMA
it's not clear how you can do rights or
甚至在锁定方案中使用DMA进行读取，因为有人必须执行
even reads using our DMA in a locking
scheme because somebody has to enforce
锁，我对此有点暂定，因为我怀疑
the locks I'm being a little tentative
about this because I suspect that with
更加智能的DMA NIC，可以支持更广泛的操作，例如
more clever our DMA NICs that could
support a wider range of operations like
原子测试并设置您有一天可能能够执行
atomic test and set
you might someday be able to do a
纯单侧RDMA的锁定方案，但是服务器场做不到，那么什么服务器场
locking scheme with pure one-sided RDMA
but farm doesn't do it okay so what farm
实际上用作一种乐观方案，在这里，您可以
actually uses as an optimistic scheme
and here in an optimistic scheme you can
使用至少可以读取而不锁定的内容，而只是读取不想要的数据
use at least you can read without
locking you just read the data you don't
知道是否允许您读取数据或是否有人在
know yet whether you are allowed to read
the data or whether somebody else is in
修改它或您只读取数据的模型中间
the model middle of modifying it or
anything you just read the data and a
交易会使用它所发生的一切，而您也不会
transaction it uses what it whatever it
happens to be and you also don't
直接以乐观方案写入数据，而不是缓冲数据，以便您
directly write the data in optimistic
schemes instead you buffered so you
缓冲区在本地和客户端中写入，直到事务最终结束并且
buffer writes locally and in the client
until the transaction finally ends and
然后当事务最终完成时，您想尝试提交
then when the transaction finally
finishes and you want to try to commit
它有一个验证阶段，即所谓的验证阶段
it there's a validate what's called a
validation stage in which the
交易处理系统试图找出是否是实际原因
transaction processing system tries to
figure out whether the actual reason
您所做的权利与可序列化性是一致的
rights you did were consistent with
serializability that is they try to
找出哦，有人在我阅读数据时写数据，如果他们
figure out oh was somebody writing the
data while I was reading it and if they
小男孩，我们无法进行此交易，因为
were boy
we can't commit this transaction because
它使用垃圾而不是一致的读取值进行计算，因此如果
it computed with garbage instead of
consistent read values and so if the
验证成功，则提交，如果验证失败，则提交
validation succeeds then you commit and
if the validation doesn't succeed if you
在您尝试使用其他数据时发现其他人弄乱了数据
detect somebody else was messing with
the data while you were trying to use it
在终止时，这意味着如果您正在阅读或写作时有冲突
at abort so that means that if there's
conflicts if you're reading or writing
数据和其他一些事务也在同时修改
data and some other transactions also
modifying at the same time
乐观方案在那时会中止，因为计算已经
optimistic schemes abort at that point
because the computation is already
在提交点错误，即您已经读取了损坏数据
incorrect at the commit point that is
you already read the damage data you
不应该阅读，所以没有办法例如阻止您知道
weren't supposed to read so there's no
way to for example block you know until
事情还好，相反交易已经有点
things are okay
instead the transactions already kind of
中毒了，只能中止并且可以尝试一下，以便农场使用
poisoned and just has to abort and
possibly be try okay so farm uses
乐观，因为他希望能够使用单面RDMA来读取
optimistic because he wants to be able
to use one-sided RDMA to just read
不管那里有什么很快，所以这个设计真的是由于使用
whatever's there very quickly so this
this design was really forced by use of
我们的DMA，通常是用于乐观并发控制的OCC的缩写
our DMA this is often abbreviated OCC
for optimistic concurrency control all
对，然后有趣的事情是乐观并发控制协议
right and then the interesting thing an
optimistic concurrency control protocols
验证的工作原理您如何实际检测到其他人
is how validation works how do you
actually detect that somebody else was
在尝试使用数据时编写数据，这实际上主要是
writing the data while you were trying
to use it and that's actually mainly
将会是我在本讲课其余部分谈论的内容
gonna be what I talked about in the rest
of this lecture and just again though
只是将其退回设计的顶层，这是在做什么
just to retire this back to the top
level of the design what this is doing
对于Farm来说，读取可以使用单面RDMA，因为因此
for farm is that the reads can use
one-sided RDMA because and therefore be
速度非常快，因为我们稍后要检查读取是否还好
extremely fast because we're gonna check
later whether the reads were okay all
正确的农场研究原型，不支持续集
right farms a research prototype it
doesn't support things like sequel it
支持用于交易的相当简单的API，这仅仅是为了
supports a fairly simple API for
transactions this is the API just to
让您了解交易代码的实际外观，如果您
give you a tease for what a transaction
code might actually look like if you
进行交易时，必须清除交易开始，因为我们
have a transaction it's gotta to clear
the start of the transaction because we
需要说哦，这组特定的原因权利需要作为一种
need to say oh this particular set of
Reason rights needs to occur as a
完成交易，代码通过调用TX create声明新交易
complete transaction the code declares a
new transaction by calling TX create
我认为从2014年起
this is all laid out by the way in the
paper I think from 2014 a slightly
同一作者的较早论文，您创建了一个新交易，然后
earlier paper by the same authors
you create a new transaction and then
您必须明确读取这些函数才能读取对象，并且必须提供一个
you explicitly read those functions to
read objects and you have to supply an
对象标识符OID，指示您要读取的对象，然后您会得到
object identifier an OID indicating what
object you want to read then you get
返回一些对象，您可以在本地内存中修改该对象，而我们没有
back some object and you can modify the
object in local memory and we didn't
写它，你有它的副本，你已经从服务器读取了TX
write it you have a copy of it that
you've read from the server the TX read
从服务器返回，所以您知道您可能会增加对象中的某些字段
back from the server so you know you
might increment some field in the object
然后当您想更新对象时，就一次又一次地调用此TX
and then when you want to update an
object you call this TX right and again
您给它提供对象ID和新的对象内容，最后在
you give it the object ID and the new
object contents and finally when you're
通过所有这些，您必须告诉助手执行此操作
through with all of this you've got to
tell the assistant to commit this
交易实际上会进行验证，如果交易成功，则会导致
transaction actually do validation and
if it succeeds cause the rights to
真正生效并可见，您将此提交例程称为
really take effect and be visible and
you call this commit routine the
社区团队在图4中运行了很多东西，我们将讨论
community team runs a whole bunch of
stuff in figure 4 which we'll talk about
并返回此正常值，需要告知应用程序哦
and it returns this okay value and it's
required to tell the application oh did
提交成功还是被中止了，所以我们需要返回这个好的返回
the commit succeed or was it aborted so
we need the return this okay return
值，您知道正确地表明交易成功了，好吧
valued you know correctly indicate by
the transaction succeeded okay there's
一些问题是一个问题，因为如果存在争用问题，OCC将中止
some questions one is question since OCC
aborts if there's contention question is
重试是否涉及指数回退，否则似乎
whether retries involve exponential
back-off because otherwise it seems like
如果您只是立即尝试，并且有很多交易
if you just instantly be tried and that
there were a lot of transactions all
试图在同一时间更新所有相同值
trying to update the same value at the
same time they'd all aboard they'd all
重试并浪费大量时间，我不知道该问题的答案
retry and waste a lot of time and I
don't know the answer to that question I
不记得看到他们在论文中提到指数回退了，但是
don't remember seeing them mentioning
exponential back-off in the paper but it
重试之间的延迟和增加的意义很大
would make a huge amount of sense to
delay between retries and to increase
延迟给某人成功的机会很像
the delay to give somebody a chance of
succeeding this is much like the
筏子的随机化收集了坦纳的另一个问题是农场
randomization of the raft collects
Tanner's another question is the farm
API在本质上更接近无后继数据库，是的，您知道这是一种
API closer in spirit to a no sequel
database yeah you know that's one way of
查看它确实没有任何花哨的查询内容，例如
viewing it it really that it doesn't
have any of the fancy query stuff like
例如加入续集，它实际上是一种非常低级的
joins for example that sequel has it's
really a very low-level kind of
读写接口以及事务支持，因此您可以对其进行排序
readwrite interface plus the transaction
support so you you can sort of view it
作为没有续集的数据库，也许可以进行交易，这就是
as a no sequel database maybe with with
transactions all right this is what a
事务看起来像这些都是库创建的
transaction looks like and these are all
these are library calls created
读/写提交提交作为一种实际运行的复杂的写调用
read/write commit commit as a sort of
complex write recall that actually runs
事务协调器代码首先是两阶段提交的罕见变体
the transaction coordinator code first
what a rare variant of two-phase commit
在图四中描述的只是重复说
this described in figure four just
repeat that the while the recall goes
关闭并实际上在本地读取相关服务器的正确调用
off and actually reads the relevant
server the right call just locally
然后缓冲新的修改对象，并且仅在提交时对象
buffers then the new the modified object
and it's only in commit that the objects
发送到服务器，这些对象ID实际上是
are sent to the servers these object IDs
are actually compound identifiers for
对象，它们包含两个部分，一个是识别区域，即
objects and they contain two parts one
is the identify a region which is that
所有服务器的所有内存均分为这些区域，并且
all the memory of all the servers is
split up into these regions and the
配置管理器跟踪哪些服务器复制哪个区域
configuration manager sort of tracks
which servers replicate which region
号码，所以这里有一个原因号码，然后您就知道了
number so there's a reason number in
here and then and then you you know you
客户端可以在表中查找给定的当前主数据库和备份数据库
client can look up in a table the
current primary and backups for a given
区域编号，然后有一个地址，例如直接存储器
region number and then there's an
address such as the straight memory
该区域内的地址，因此客户使用原因编号来选择
address within that region and so the
client uses the reason number to pick
与备份中的主要对象进行对话，然后将地址移交给我们的DMA
the primary in the backup to talk to and
then it hands the address to the our DMA
NIC并告诉它外观，请阅读此地址以获取此地址
NIC and tells it look please read at
this address in order to get fetch this
宾语
object
好吧，我们必须避免的另一个细节是看一下
alright another piece of detail we have
to get out of the way is to look at the
服务器内存布局我在任何一台服务器中，都有很多东西
server memory layout I'm in any one
server there's a bunch of stuff in
内存，所以一部分就是服务器在其内存中是否有
memory so one part is that the server
has in its memory its if it's it's
复制一个或多个区域时，它具有实际区域，或者是什么原因
replicating one or more regions it has
the actual regions and or what a reason
包含一大堆这些对象，每个对象都有很多
contains is a whole bunch of these
objects and each object there's a lot of
坐在内存中的对象每个对象中都有一个标头，其中包含
objects objects sitting in memory each
object has in it a header which contains
版本号，所以这些是版本化的对象，但仅每个对象
the version number so these are
versioned objects but each object only
一次有一个版本，所以这是版本号，高位表示
has one version at a time so this is
version number and in the high bit let
我在这里再试一次，每个版本号的高位是一个锁定标志，所以在
me try again here and the high bit of
each version number is a lock flag so in
对象的标头有一个锁定标志和高位，然后是一个版本
the header of an object there's a lock
flag and the high bit and then a version
编号，然后是对象的实际数据，因此每个对象
number in a little bit and then the
actual data of the object so each object
具有相同的服务器内存，具有相同的布局，高位有锁定位
has the same servers memory it's the
same layout a lock bit in the high bit
和当前版本号，每次系统写入时
and the current version number a little
bit and every time the system writes
修改对象会增加版本号，让我们看看
modifies an object it increases the
version number and let's see how the
几分钟后还会在服务器的内存中使用锁定位
lock bits are used in a couple minutes
in addition in the server's memory there
是一对提示队列的消息队列，并在其中每隔一台计算机记录一个
are pairs of cue pairs of message queues
and logs one for every other computer in
系统，这意味着您知道在服务器中是否还有其他四台服务器
the system so that means that you know
if there's four other servers in the
系统正在运行，或者是否有四个服务器在运行
system that are running or if there's
four servers that are running
事务中将有四个日志存储在内存中
transactions there's going to be four
logs sitting in memory that can be
随我们的DMA附加到其他每台服务器上，这意味着
appended to with our DMA one for each of
the other servers and that means that
每台其他计算机都可以运行一个事务，这意味着
one for each of the other computers can
run transactions so that means that the
交易代码在您身上运行，所以您知道其中的数量是
transaction code running on you know so
number of them you know it's the
交易代码在计算机上运行到它想与该服务器对话的时间，以及
transaction code running on computer to
when it wants to talk to this server and
附加到它的日志中，并看到它实际上将附加到服务器二
append to its log which as well see it's
actually going to append to server twos
登录此服务器的内存，因此浮动的队列总数为N平方
log in this servers memory so there's a
total N squared of these queues floating
在每个服务器的内存中，似乎确实存在
around in in in each servers memory and
it certainly seems like there's actually
一组原本应该是我的日志将是非易失性的，然后
one set of logs which are meant to be I
would non-volatile and then also
可能是一组单独的消息队列，仅用于更多的RPC
possibly a separate set of message
queues which are used just for more RPC
就像再次通信，每个服务器一个，一个队列消息传入
like communication again one in each
server one queue message incoming
通过我们的DMA写入的每其他服务器的消息多维数据集实际上可以正常写入
message cube per other server written
with our DMA writes all right actually
接下来要谈的是论文的四年级
the next thing to talk about is a year
four in the paper
这是第4英尺，这说明了场使用的occ提交协议和
this is feet four and this explains the
occ commit protocol that farm uses and
我要一步一步地完成所有步骤，实际上首先
I'm gonna go through mostly steps one by
one and actually to to begin with I'm
只会把重点放在这并发控制部分
gonna focus only on the concurrency
control part of this it turns out these
步骤还执行复制以及实现可序列化的事务，但是
steps also do replication as well as
implement serializable transactions but
稍后我们将讨论复制以实现容错功能
we'll talk about the replication for
fault tolerance a little bit later okay
所以发生的第一件事是执行阶段，这就是TX读取
so the first thing that happens is the
execute phase and this is the TX reads
然后TX写原因写客户事务正在做，所以每个
and TX writes the reason writes that the
client transaction is doing and so each
这些箭头在这里意味着事务在计算机C上运行
of these arrows here what this means is
that the transaction runs on computer C
当需要阅读某些东西时
and when
needs to read something it uses
单侧RDMA，我们只需从相关的主服务器内存中读取它即可
one-sided RDMA we to simply read it out
of the relevant primary servers memory
所以我们在这里得到的是主备份主备份主备份为三个
so what we got here was a primary backup
primary backup primary backup for three
不同的分片，我们正在想象我们的交易从
different shards and we're imagining
that our transaction read something from
这些碎片中的每个碎片都使用单向RDMA的一个对象，这意味着
one object from each of these shards
using one-sided RDMA reason that means
每五个微秒都快得令人眼花so乱，所以客户端可以读取所有内容
these blindingly fast five microseconds
each okay so the client reads everything
它需要读取事务，也要写入任何内容
it needs to read for the transaction
also anything that's going to write it
首先读取并且必须执行此读取必须首先读取，因为它需要
first reads and it has to do it do this
read has to first read because it needs
获取版本号初始版本号就可以了
to get the version number
the initial version number all right so
这是执行阶段，然后在事务调用TX时提交以指示
that's the execute phase then when the
transaction calls TX commits to indicate
它完全完成了您知道的TX commit调用上的库
that it's totally done the library on
the you know the TX commit call on on
客户端充当事务协调器并运行整个协议
the client acts as a transaction
coordinator and runs this whole protocol
这是两阶段提交的一种精心设计的版本，第一阶段是
which is a kind of elaborate version of
two-phase commit the first phase and
这是根据消息轮数来描述的，因此交易协调员
that's described in terms of rounds of
messages so the transaction coordinator
发送一堆LOC消息，等待它们回复然后验证
sends a bunch of LOC messages and wait
for them to reply and then validate
消息和所有回复的浪费，因此提交的第一阶段
messages and waste for the all the
replies so the first phase in the commit
协议是此阶段客户端发送的锁定费用
protocol is the lock fees in this phase
what the client is sending is it sends
对于每个主对象，对于客户端的每个对象，对象的标识
to each primary the identity of the
object in for each object for clients
并需要将更新的对象发送到相关的主对象，因此它
written and needs to send that updated
object to the relevant primary so it
将更新后的对象作为主对象发送为新对象
sends the updated objects the primary
and as an as a new log entry in the
您为此客户端知道的主要日志，因此该客户端确实已在滥用
primaries log you know for this client
so the client really abusing already
附加到主日志中的对象，它的附加对象是
made to append to the primaries log and
what it's appending is the object ID of
对象的命令要写入客户端的版本号
the writ of the object wants to write
the version number that the client
读取对象和新值时的初始读取
initially read when it read the object
and the new value
因此，它将您的电话号码和新值的对象附加到
so it appends the object of yours number
and new value to the primary logon for
它在其中写入对象的主要负责人，所以我
the primary beach of the charge that
it's written an object in so these I
猜猜这是怎么回事，这笔交易写了两个不同的
guess what's going on here is that the
this transaction wrote two different
在主对象上一个对象，在主对象上另一个对象则知道何时完成此操作
objects one on primary one and the other
on primary to know when this is done
当交易协调员恢复正常时，现在这些
when the transaction coordinator gets
back the well alright so now the these
新的日志记录位于主数据库的主日志中
new log records are sitting in the logs
of the primaries the primary though has
实际主动处理这些日志条目，因为它需要检查和
to actually actively process these log
entries because it needs to check and
他们会进行一些涉及验证的检查，以查看
they sort of do a number of checks
involved with validation to see if the
如果此主要对象是事务的一部分，则可以允许提交，因此
if this primary is part of the
transaction can be allowed to commit so
在这一点上，我们必须等待每个主数据库轮询此客户端日志
at this point we have to wait for each
primary to to poll the this clients log
在主内存中，看到有一个新的日志条目并处理该新日志
in the primaries memory see that there's
a new log entry and process that new log
条目，然后发送是或否的投票，以表明是否愿意
entry and then send a yes-or-no vote to
say whether it is or is not willing to
做好交易的一部分，那么主要交易者在交易时会做什么
do its part of the transaction all right
so what does the primary do when it's
轮询循环首先查看来自客户端的传入锁定日志条目，如果
polling loop sees that an incoming lock
log entry from a client first of all if
具有对象ID的对象当前被阻止，则主要对象
that object with the object ID is
currently blocked then the primary
拒绝此锁定消息，并使用RDMA将消息发送回客户端
rejects this lock message and sends back
a message to the client using RDMA
说不，不允许这项交易进行，我投票否，
saying no that this transaction cannot
be allowed to proceed I'm voting no and
两阶段提交，这将导致事务协调器中止
two-phase commit and that will cause the
transaction coordinator to abort the
交易，另一个未锁定，则主要交易的下一步是
transaction and the other is not locked
then the next thing the primary does is
检查它检查的版本号，以确保该版本号
check the version numbers it checks to
make sure that the version number that
客户端发送的是最初读取的客户端的版本号是
the client sent it that is the version
number of the client originally read is
保持不变，如果版本号更改，则表示
unchanged and if the version numbers
changed that means that between when our
事务读取并且当它写入时，如果
transaction read and when it wrote
somebody else wrote the object if the
版本号已更改，因此版本号再次更改了
version numbers changed and so the
version numbers changed again the
主服务器将回答“否”，并禁止继续进行交易，但如果
primary will respond no and forbid the
transaction from continuing but if the
版本号与未设置的锁相同
version number is the same in the lock
that's not set
而主服务器将设置锁定，并向
and the primary will set the lock and
return a positive response back to the
客户端，因为主服务器的多线程在多个CPU上运行
client now because the primary's
multi-threaded running on multiple CPUs
可能还有其他事务，可能还有其他CPU在读取其他
and there may be other transactions
there may be other CPUs reading other
来自其他客户端的传入日志提示同时在同一主服务器上
incoming log cues from other clients at
the same time on the same primary there
可能是不同交易之间的竞赛或锁定了时钟记录
may be races between different
transactions or lock the clock record
尝试修改同一对象的来自不同事务的处理，因此
processing from different transactions
trying to modify the same object so the
主要实际上使用原子指令进行比较和交换
primary actually uses an atomic
instruction a compare and swap
指令以检查版本号并锁定并设置
instruction in order to both check check
the version number and lock and set the
将那个版本号锁定为原子操作，这就是原因
lock a bit on that version number as an
atomic operation and this is the reason
为什么它的锁必须在版本号的高位，以便
why the lock of it has to be in the high
bits of the version number so that a
一条指令可以对版本号和锁进行比较和交换
single instruction can do a compare and
swap on the version number and the lock
现在好一点要注意的是，如果对象已经锁定
bit okay now one thing to note is that
if the objects already locked
没有阻塞，没有等待锁释放的主要时间
there's no blocking there's no waiting
for the lock to be released the primary
只是发回一个知道是否有其他交易将其锁定好了
simply sends back a know if some other
transaction has it locked alright any
关于委员会的锁定费的问题可以追溯到趋势中
questions about the lock fees of of
Committee all right back in the trend
负责代理其交易协调员的客户
head in the client which is acting his
transaction coordinator it waits for
分片中所有原语的响应，因此对于每个
responses from all the primaries from
the primaries of the shard so for every
如果交易中有人需要，则拒绝交易
object that the transaction modified if
any of them say no if they need them
拒绝交易，然后交易协调员中止整个交易
reject the transaction then the
transaction coordinator aborts the whole
交易并实际上向所有主要机构发出消息说我
transaction and actually sends out
messages to all the primaries saying I
改变了主意，我毕竟不想做这个交易，但是如果他们
changed my mind I don't want to commit
this transaction after all but if they
所有主要答案都回答是，然后交易
all answered yes of all the primaries
answer yes then the transaction
协调员认为这决定了交易实际上可以提交，但是
coordinator thinks that decides that the
transaction can actually commit but the
初选当然不知道他们是否都投了赞成票
primaries of course don't know whether
they all voted yes
还是不这样，交易协调员必须通知每个球首要
or not so the transaction coordinator
has to notify every ball the primary so
是的，每个人都投票赞成，所以请确实做到这一点以及
yes deed everybody voted yes so please
do actually commit this and the way the
客户端这样做是通过将另一条记录附加到主服务器的日志中
client does this is by appending another
record to the logs of the primaries for
这次每个修改的对象都是提交备份记录，它是挂起的
each modified object this time it's a
commit backup record that it's a pending
这次是交易协调员，很抱歉我确实提交了
and the this time the transaction
coordinator I'm sorry I did commit
我正在跳过有效性的主节点，现在我没有谈论备份
primary I'm skipping over valide didn't
commit backup for now I'll talk about
那些以后，所以暂时忽略那些事务协调员
those later so just ignore those for the
moment the transaction coordinator goes
继续提交主笔，将笔主要提交到每个主笔日志的笔
on to commit primary sends pens that
commit primary to each primaries log and
事务协调器只需要等待硬件RDMA
the transaction coordinator only has to
wait for the hardware RDMA
确认它不必等待主要的实际处理
acknowledgments it doesn't have to wait
for the primary just actually process
该日志记录了事务协调器，它一旦出现
the log record the transaction
coordinator it turns out as soon as it
从任何一个原语中得到一个确认，它可以返回是
gets a single acknowledgment from any of
the primaries it can return yes the okay
等于表示交易六的交易的真实性
equals true to the transactions
signifying that the transaction six
成功之后，还有另一个阶段
succeeded and then there's another stage
later on where the once the transaction
协调员知道每个主要人员都知道交易已协调
coordinator knows that every primary
knows that the transaction coordinated
提交，您可以告诉所有主数据库，他们可以丢弃所有日志
committed you can tell all the primaries
that they can discard all the log
这项交易的输入现在好了，还有最后一件事
entries for this transaction okay now
there's one last thing that has to
发生在看原木的原木民意调查长的
happen the primaries which are looking
at the logs their polling the Long's
他们会注意到在某个时候有一个提交主记录，然后
they'll notice that there's a commit
primary record at some point and then on
接收提交主日志条目的主数据库将知道它
the primary that receives the commit
primary log entry will it knows that it
之前已经锁定了该对象，并且该对象必须仍然被锁定，因此
had locked that object previously and
that the object must still be locked so
主要对象将要做的是使用新的对象更新其内存中的对象
what the primary will do is update the
object in its memory with the new
以前在锁定消息中发送的内容，我正在增加
contents that were previously sent in
the lock message I'm increment the
与该对象关联的版本号，最后清除上的锁定位
version number associated with that
object and finally clear the lock bit on
该对象，这意味着它是主要对象
that object and what that means is that
as soon as a primary
接收并处理提交主要日志消息，因为它清除了
receives and processes a commit primary
log message it may since it clears the
锁定一点并更新数据，很可能将此新数据公开给其他人
lock a bit and updates the data it may
well expose this new data to other
交易之后的其他交易都可以免费使用
transactions other transactions after
this point are free to use it are free
使用它的新值和新版本号的对象，我要
to use the object with its new value and
new version number all right I'm gonna
在开始考虑之前，先对机械提出任何问题的例子
do an example any questions about the
machinery before I start thinking about
一个例子随时可以问问题，那么一个例子怎么样
an example feel free to ask questions
any time alright so how about an example
假设我们有两个事务，事务一和事务二，
let's suppose we have two transactions
transaction one and transaction two and
他们俩都想做同一件事，只是想增加XX是
they're both trying to do the same thing
they both just wanna increment X X is
对象坐在一些服务器内存中，所以我们两个
the object sitting off in some servers
memory so so both we got two
在我们实际调查之前，正在运行的事务
transactions running running through
this before we look into what actually
碰巧我们应该提醒自己什么是
happens we should remind ourselves what
the valid possibilities are for the
这样的结果就可以保证可序列化服务器场
outcomes so and that's all about
serializability farm guaranteed
序列化功能，这意味着无论服务器场实际做什么
serialize ability so that means that
whatever farm actually does it has to be
相当于一次执行这两个事务中的某个事务，因此
equivalent to some one at a time
execution of these two transactions so
我们可以看到，如果t1运行了，那么您将看到结果，然后严格
we're allowed to see was the results you
would see if t1 ran and then strictly
之后t2运行，或者我们可以看到如果t2运行并且随后可能发生的结果
afterwards t2 ran or we can see the
results that could ensue if t2 ran and
然后t1运行，这是现在唯一的可能性，事实上场是
then t1 run those are the only
possibilities now in fact farm is
有权中止交易，因此我们还必须考虑可能性
entitled to abort a transaction so we
also have to consider the possibility
这两个交易之一中止了，或者实际上他们都中止了我，因为
that one of the two transactions aborted
or indeed that they both aborted I since
他们都在做同一件事，但有一定的对称性
they're doing both doing the same thing
there's a certain amount of symmetry
在这里，一种可能性是他们俩都承诺，这意味着有两种
here so one possibility is that they
both committed and that means two
发生增量，因此有一个合法的可能性，即X等于2并且
increments happen so one legal
possibilities that X is equal to 2 and
无论是TX，还是必须同意事物是否
both then the TX
it has to agree with whether things a
位，中止或提交，以便两个事务都需要返回CTX提交
bit or aborted or committed so that both
transactions need to CTX commit returned
在这种情况下，确实如此，另一种可能性是，其中只有一笔交易
true in this case another possibility is
that only one of them transactions
提交，另一个终止，然后我们只想看到一个真实的
committed and the other aborted and then
we want to see only one true and the
其他错误和另一种可能性，也许他们都放弃了我们不认为
other false and another possibilities
maybe they both aborted we don't think
这可能会发生，但实际上是合法的，因此X不变
this could necessarily happen but it's
actually legal so that X isn't changed
我们希望双方都能从
and we want both to get false back from
TX commit，所以我们最好不要看到除了这三个选项以外的任何东西
TX commit so we better better not see
anything other than these three options
好的，所以当然会发生什么取决于时间，所以我要
all right so of course what happens
depends on the timing so I'm going to
集成了提交协议可以尽早使用的各种不同方式
integrate out various different ways
that the commit protocol could in early
即使是为了方便起见，我也方便地提醒您实际的提交
even for convenience I have a handy
reminder of what the actual commit
协议在这里，所以一种可能性是它们准确地按步运行
protocol is here so one possibility is
that they run exactly in lockstep they
都在同一时间发送他们的所有消息他们都在同一时间阅读
both send all their messages at the same
time they both read at the same time I'm
假设如果X和X同时读取，则X起始为零
going to assume that X starts out as
zero if they both read at the same time
我们将看到零，我想他们都在
that we're going to see zero I assume
they both sent out lakh messages at the
同时
same time
实际上，它们在日志消息中附带的值为“一”，因为
and indeed they accompany their log
messages with the value one since
他们在上面加1，如果他们走路的话就提交，说是
they're adding 1 to it and that if they
commit if they walk messages say yes
那么如果他们两个都同时提交，他们就会这样做，如果这是
then they would if they did both commit
at the same time so if if this is the
场景将会发生什么，为什么
scenario what's going to happen and why
您
you
他们喜欢举手示意并猜测危险
they like to raise their hand and hazard
a guess
嗯，这是一个很好的领域，因为这是单方面的读不能
well that's really good field to be
since that's a one-sided read can't
可能失败，他们俩都会向所有对象发送实际上相同的步行消息
possibly fail they're both gonna send in
fact identical walk messages to whatever
主要持有对象X，我都发送相同的版本号，但一个版本
primary holds object X and I both send
the same version number but a version
他们读取的数字和相同的值，因此原色将记录为
number they read and the same value so
the primaries gonna see to log meant to
在两个不同的传入日志中记录消息，假设它们正在运行
log messages in two different incoming
logs assuming these are running on
不同的客户，现在到底发生了什么，由我们自己决定
different clients and exactly what
happens now is slightly left up to our
本文的想象力，但我认为这两个传入的日志消息可能是
imagination by the paper but I think the
two incoming log messages could be
在主节点上的不同内核上并行处理，但关键
processed in parallel on different cores
on the primary but the critical
主要的指令是原子测试，并且完全设置或比较并交换
instruction of the primary is the atomic
test and set or compare and swap exactly
某人的志愿者，其中一个将得到比较和交换的答案
somebody's volunteer the answer that one
of them will get to the compare and swap
指令优先，无论哪个核心，我猜比较和交换指令
instruction first and whichever core I
guess the compare and swap instruction
首先，它将在该对象版本上设置锁定位，然后观察
first it'll set the lock bit on that
objects version and will observe the
锁没有事先设置，每个人都执行原子
lock a bit wasn't previously set which
everyone executes the atomic
比较和交换秒将观察已经设置的锁定，我的意思是他是
compare-and-swap second will observe the
lock that's already set I mean he's the
两者之一将返回是，另外两个将失败锁定，请观察
one of the two will return yes and the
other two will fail the lock observe the
锁已经设置为未成熟否，您知道它是对称的，我只是要
lock is already set immature no and you
know it for symmetry I'm just going to
假设向主数据库的事务发送了否，则该事务向
imagine that transaction to the primary
sends back a no so the transaction to
使用客户端代码将中止事务1我已经获得了锁，并返回了yes
use client code will abort transaction 1
I've got the lock got a yes back and it
实际上会在主要对象实际获得时提交
will actually commit when it come
it's when the primary actually gets the
提交消息，它将安装更新的对象
commit message it'll install the updated
object
你知道增量来清除锁定位增量版本并返回
you know increments to to clear the lock
bit increment the version and return
是的，这会说是正确的，因为其他主要学生发回了我，
true this is gonna say true because the
other primary sent back I know that
表示TX提交将在此处返回false，最终值为x
means that TX commits gonna return false
here and the final value would be x
等于那是我们允许的结果之一，但当然不是唯一的结果
equals one that was one of our allowed
outcomes but of course it's not the only
对此有任何疑问，如如何播放或广泛执行
in are leaving any questions about how
this played out or wide executed the way
它做了
it did
好吧，所以还有其他可能的交织，怎么样
okay so there's other possible
interleavings so how about how about
让我们想象一下交易2首先执行拍子
this one let's imagine that transaction
2 does the beat first
她对读取的内容并发与否与事务无关紧要
she doesn't really matter what the reads
are concurrent or not then transaction
一个人不读，然后交易进行得更快一点，它得到了
one doesn't read and then transaction
went a little bit faster and it gets its
锁定消息并回复，然后返回提交，然后再提交
lock message in and a reply and gets a
commit back and then afterwards
事务二再次执行并在可能的情况下发送锁定消息
transaction two gets going again and
sends a lock message in if it could
提交，所以这次会发生什么
commit so what happens this time
这个法律专员会成功吗，因为没有理由
well is this law commissioner is gonna
be succeed because there's no reason to
相信设置了锁定位，因为第二个锁定消息没有
believe there's a lock bit is set
because the second lock message hasn't
即使是已发送的消息，我们也会将锁定设置为该提交的提交消息
even been sent message we'll set the
lock the commit message this commit
主消息实际上应该稍微清除锁定，以便锁定位为
primary message should actually clear
the lock a bit so the lock bit will be
在t2普查时清除，将其锁定条目插入到主日志中，因此这
clear by the time t2 census inserts its
lock entry in primaries log so this the
主用户此时看不到锁定设置，是的，所以有人
primary won't see the lock a bit set at
this point yeah so somebody's
自愿要求该主要人员看到的是版本号，因此
volunteered that what this primary will
see is that the version number so the
锁定消息中包含交易原始版本号
the lock message contains the version
number the transaction to originally
读，所以主要的要等一会，因为提交主要
read and so the primary is gonna see
wait a minute this since commit primary
版本号的增量，主要版本会看到该版本
increments of version number the the
primary is gonna see that the version
数字是错误的，现在实际对象上的数字更高，所以它是
number is wrong there's numbers now
higher on the real object and so it's
实际上会发回一个无回应给协调员和协调员
actually gonna send back a a no response
to the coordinator and the coordinator
将中止此交易，我们将再次获得x等于1
is gonna abort this transaction and
again we're gonna get x equals 1 one of
交易返回true，另一个返回false，与最终结果相同
the transactions return true the other
returned false which is the same final
结果与以前一样，并且允许对此有任何疑问
稍微不同的情况就好像并且实际上可以
slightly different scenario would be as
if and actually okay the slightly
我会想到的另一种情况是提交
different scenario I was gonna think of
think of was one in which the commit
信息被盗，它发生在此锁定之后，这与
message was stole it happened after this
lock this is essentially the same as the
此事务在此事务中设置了锁的第一种情况
first scenario in which this transaction
got the lock set in this transaction
观察到的锁好吧，每个人的最后一个场景让我们假设
observed lock okay
everyone one last scenario let's suppose
我们看到这个
we see this
这次会发生什么[音乐]
what's going to happen this time
[Music]
是的，当然有人会给出正确的答案
通过，因为在第一笔交易中没有争用
through because there's no contention in
the first transaction the second
事务在读取X时实际上会看到新的版本号为
transaction when it goes to read X will
actually see the new version number as
通过在主数据库上的提交主要处理增加，因此它将看到
incremented by the commit primary
processing on the primary so it'll see
新版本号不会设置的锁，因此当它转到
the new version number the lock that
won't be set and so then when it goes to
将其锁定日志条目发送到锁定了处理代码的主锁
send its lock log entry to the primary
lock lock that locked processing code in
主要公司的锁没有设置和版本是一样的不是这是
the primary Co the locks not set and the
version is the same hasn't this is the
最新版本及其所有我想提交的内容，因此，我们
latest version and it all I want to
commit and so for this the outcome we're
会看到x等于2，因为这不仅读取了新版本um
gonna see is x equals 2 because this
read not only read the new version um
但实际上读取的是一个新值，因此在这里是不正确的，
but actually read the new value which
was one so this is incorrect here and
对TX commit的两次调用都将为true是，正确的是x等于2
both calls to TX commit will be true yes
that's right succeed it with x equals 2
好的，所以您知道这在这种情况下确实可以解决
all right so you know this happened to
work out in these cases the intuition
为什么乐观并发控制提供了可序列化性的原因
behind why optimistic concurrency
control provides serializability why it
为什么它基本上检查确实发生的执行与
why it basically checks that the
execution that did happen is the same as
一次执行一个人的直觉本质上是，如果没有
a one at a time execution essentially
the intuition is that if there was no
发生冲突的交易，则版本号和锁定位将不具有
conflicting transaction then the version
numbers and the lock bits won't have
如果没有其他人将这些对象弄乱了，那就改变了，你知道我会看到相同的
changed if nobody else is messing with
these objects you know I'll see the same
交易结束时的版本号，就像我们初次阅读时一样
version numbers at the end of the
transaction as we did when we first read
对象，而如果我们之间的交易发生冲突
the object whereas if there is a
conflicting transaction between when we
读取对象，当我们尝试进行更改时，该冲突
read the object and when we try to
commit a change and that conflicting
修改了一些东西，如果它真的开始提交了，我们将看到一个新的
modified something then if it actually
started to commit we will see a new
版本号或锁定位设置，以便比较版本号
version number or a lock a bit set so
the comparison of the version numbers
并在第一次读取对象与最终读取之间锁定位
and lock bits between when you first
read the object and when you finally
提交，它可以告诉您是否有其他其他提交到对象中
commit it kind of tells you whether some
other commits to the objects snuck in
当您正确使用它们时，您知道这里要记住的很酷的事情
while you were using them all right and
you know the cool thing to remember here
就是这样允许我们使用这种乐观模式进行读取
is that this allowed us to do the reads
the use of this optimistic schema which
实际上，仅当我们第一次使用允许我们执行以下操作的数据时，我们才真正检查锁
we don't actually check the locks only
when we first use the data allowed us to
使用这个非常快的一侧已经可以读取数据并
use this extremely fast one sided
already ma reads to read the data and
可以取得高性能，所以到目前为止，我在没有验证的情况下对此进行了解释，
get high performance ok so the way I've
explained it so far without validate and
没有提交备份是系统工作的方式，但是正如我所看到的，validate是
without commit back up is the way the
system works but as I see validate is
仅读取对象但不写入并提交的一种优化
sort of an optimization for just reading
an object but not writing it and commit
作为容错计划的一部分，我想我会
back up as part of the scheme for fault
tolerance I think I'm gonna a few
我们要讲的几分钟是关于验证，所以验证阶段是
minutes we have left I want to talk
about validate so the validate stage is
这是一种用于处理我们只能由
it's an optimization for to treat
objects that we're only read by the
交易，而且我还没有写信，如果
transaction and I'm not written and it's
going to be particularly interesting if
这是一个直接的只读事务，它没有进行任何修改，您知道
it's a straight read-only transaction
that modified nothing and you know the
最优化的是，交易协调员可以
optimization is that it's going to be
that the transaction coordinator can
用非常快的单面读取而不是单面执行验证
execute the validate with a one-sided
read that's extremely fast rather than
不得不在日志上放一些东西并等待主要的人看到我们的日志
having to put something on a log and
wait for the primary to see our log
进入并考虑它，这样可以验证单面B将是
entry and think about it so this
validates one-sided B is going to be
快得多，它将本质上替换仅用于对象的锁
much much faster it's gonna essentially
replace lock for objects that would only
读起来会更快
read it's gonna be much faster
基本上这里发生的是验证操作是
basically what's going on here is that
the what what the validate does is the
事务协调器refetch是对象标头，因此您知道
transaction coordinator refetch is the
object header so you know it would have
在执行阶段读取对象时，说一个对象
read an object say this object in the
execute phase when it's committing it
而不是发送锁定消息，而是获取对象命中标头并检查
instead of sending a lock message it be
fetches the object hit header and checks
现在的版本号是否与第一次时的版本号相同
whether the version number now is the
same as the version number when it first
读取对象，它还会检查它的锁是否清楚，所以这就是
read the object and it also checks if
the lock of it is clear so so that's how
它可以正常工作，而不是设置锁定消息
it works
so instead of setting a lock message
发送此验证消息对于只读操作应该要快得多，因此
send this validate message should be
much faster for a read-only operation so
让我提出另一个交易示例并运行它的工作方式
let me put up another transaction
example and run through it how it works
假设x和y最初为0，如果X相等，则有两个事务t1
let's suppose x and y are initially 0 we
have two transactions t1 if X is equal
归零，则y等于1，T 2表示Y是否为零
to zero set y equal one and T two says
if Y is zero
说x等于1，但这绝对是对强项的经典检验
said x equals one but this is a
absolutely classic test for strong
一致性，如果执行是可序列化的，它将是t1
consistency if the execution is
serializable it's going to be either t1
然后是t2或t2和t1
then t2 or t2 and t1 it's got to get to
see any you know corrected
实现必须获得相同的结果，一次运行一次
implementation has to get the same
results it's running them one at a time
如果运行T 1然后运行t2，则y等于1，x等于0，因为
if you run T 1 and then t2 you're gonna
get y equals 1 and x equals 0 because
第二个if语句Y已经为1，第二个if语句不起作用
the second if statement Y is already 1
the second if statement won't do
任何东西，对称地，这将使您x等于1，y等于0且
anything and symmetrically this will
give you x equals 1 and y equals 0 and
事实证明，如果您都放弃了，则x等于0 y等于0
it turns out that if you if they both
abort you can get x equals 0 y equals 0
但是绝对不允许您得到的是x等于1 y等于1那是
but what you are absolutely not allowed
to get is x equals 1 y equals 1 that's
不允许
not allowed
好的，所以我们正在寻找如何将其用作测试，看看会发生什么
ok so we're looking for how I'm going to
use this as a test see what happens with
验证，我们再次假设这两个事务执行得最多，
validate and again we're gonna suppose
these two transactions execute most so
很明显，他们绝对同时执行它，而且吃掉了
obvious cases they execute it absolutely
at the same time and it eat that's the
这是最困难的情况，因为我们读过X遇见Y
that's the hardest case okay so as we
have read of X meet Y
为什么，因为我们写了它并锁定了，为什么在这里我在这里锁定了X
why because we wrote it and lock why
here I sort of lock X here but since now
我们正在使用这种只读的验证优化功能，这意味着该操作必须
we're using this read-only a validation
optimization that means this one has to
验证为什么这个必须验证X您知道它是红色的X但没有写
validate why this one has to validate X
you know it's a red X but didn't write
所以它会更快地验证它，也许会提交
it so it's going to validate it much
quicker and maybe it's going to commit
也许是，所以问题是我们是否按照我的描述使用了此验证
and maybe it's and so the question is if
we use this validate as I described it
只是检查版本号并锁定，但没有版本号
that just checks the version number and
lock but haven't the version number
锁没有改变但没有设置，我们会得到一个正确的答案
hasn't changed in the lock but isn't set
will we get a a correct answer
并且实际上没有两个验证都会因为两个失败而失败
and no actually both the validation is
gonna fail for both because when these
LOC消息是由相关的主要对象处理的，它们导致LOC
LOC messages were processed by the
relevant primaries they cause the LOC a
最初只是被设置的原因大概是清除锁定的原因
bit just to be set initially presumably
the the reason okay did a cleared lock
bin，但是当客户进行单方面验证时，
bin but when we come to validate even
though the client is doing the one-sided
读取X＆Y的对象标头后，将看到由设置的锁定位
read of the object header for X&Y it's
gonna see the lock bit that was set by
这些锁定请求的处理
the processing of these lock requests
因此，他们俩都将看到仅在对象上设置的锁定位
and so they're both gonna see the lock
bits set on the object that they merely
读取，它们都将中止，并且X和Y都不会被修改，因此
read and they're both going to abort and
neither X nor Y will be modified and so
那是有人注意到的正确法律结果之一
that was one of the legal outcomes
that's right somebody somebody notice
确实，这两个验证当然都会失败，有时
this indeed both validates will fail
another of course sometimes that a
交易可以通过，这确实可以解决
transaction can go through and here's a
scenario in which it does work out
这是交易之一，验证更快
this was transaction one is a little
faster validates
好吧，所以交易会发生什么快一点
all right so what's going to happen a
transaction one is a little bit faster
所以这次验证将成功，因为什么都没发生
so this time it's validates gonna
succeed because nothing has happened to
事务1何时读取它与它何时验证之间的X大概是锁
X between when transaction 1 read it and
when it validated so presumably the lock
也顺利通过，因为这里也没有人修改Y
also went through without any trouble
because nobody's modified Y here either
所以主要对此回答是肯定的，单面阅读显示没有变化
so the primary answered yes for this the
one-sided read revealed an unchanged
版本号和锁定位在此处，因此事务一可以提交，它将
version number and lock bit here and so
transaction one can commit and it will
已经增加了Y，但是如果这是主要
have incremented Y but by this point if
this is the order when the primary
当主进程是X的锁时，进程实际上就是这个
process is this actually when the
primary process is lock of X this will
也没有问题，因为当
also go through with no problem because
nobody's modified X when the primary for
Y抱歉，当客户端运行时，Y为Y处理验证
Y processes the validate for Y though
it's I'm sorry when the client running
事务2 refetch是版本号y解锁的
transaction two refetch is the version
number unlocked it for y it's either
会真正看到这取决于委员会是否在提交时进行
gonna see this really depends on whether
the committee's happen if the commit
尚未发生这个有效的a将看到锁定位已设置，因为它
hasn't happened yet this valid a will
see that the lock bit is set because it
如果已经发生提交，则将其设置回此处，然后将其锁定位
was set back here if the commit has
happened already then the lock bit of
会很清楚，但这可以验证单面阅读器会看到不同的结果
will be clear but this validate
one-sided reader will see a different
版本号比最初看到的要多，这需要有人
version number than was originally seen
and it needs somebody it's just this
回答，这样一个人就会提交，这样一个事务就会提交，
answer so one will commit so that
transaction one will commit and
交易将终止，尽管我没有时间说话
transaction to will abort
and although I don't have time to talk
关于它，如果有直接的只读事务，那么就没有
about it here if there's a straight
read-only transaction then there doesn't
需要是一个锁定阶段，而不必是纯粹的提交阶段
need to be a locking phase and there
doesn't need to be a commit phase pure
只读交易只需阅读盲读即可完成
read-only transactions can be done with
just just reading blind reads for the
读取对不起的单面RDMA读取
reads
sorry one-sided RDMA reads for the reads
一方面我已经阅读了验证信息，所以它们非常快
one-sided already me reads for the
validates and so they're extremely fast
只读事务是，不需要任何工作，
read-only transactions are and don't
require any work any attention by the
服务器如此，这是您知道的核心
server
so and this is at the heart you know
趋势这些阅读，尽管关于农场的一切都非常
trends these reads and indeed though
everything about farm is very
简化-部分由于我们的DMA，并且使用OCC，因为它基本上是
streamlined - partially due to our DMA
and it uses OCC because it's basically
为了能够在不检查锁的情况下进行读取，有一个
forced to in order to be able to do
reads without checking locks there are a
尽管事实证明乐观的并发控制确实很少
few brown downsides though it turns out
optimistic concurrency control really
如果冲突相对较少，那么冲突最有效
works best if there's relatively few
conflicts if there's conflicts all the
时间到了，交易将不得不进行，有一个你知道的
time then transactions will have to
board and there's a you know a bunch of
我已经提到过的其他限制，例如数据场都必须适合
other restrictions I already mentioned
like on farm like the data must all fit
在RAM和所有计算机中必须表示相同的数据中心
in the RAM and all the computers must
mean that the same data center
尽管如此，这在当时还是被认为是非常令人惊讶的
nevertheless this was viewed at the time
and still as just a very surprisingly
高速执行分布式事务的速度比
high-speed implementation of distributed
transactions like just much faster than
任何在生产中使用的系统，的确，硬件涉及
any system in sort of in production use
and it's true that Hardware involves a
有点异国情调，实际上取决于这种非易失性Ram方案，
little bit exotic and really depends on
this non-volatile Ram scheme and it
取决于这些特殊的RDMA NIC，而现在还不那么普遍
depends on these special RDMA NICs and
those are not particularly pervasive now
但是您可以，但是可以得到它们，并且具有这样的性能，似乎很可能
but you do but you can get them and with
performance like this it seems likely
他们将同时在观看并且已经在我身上最终将变得非常普遍
that they'll both in viewing and already
me will eventually be pretty pervasive
在数据中心中，以便人们可以玩这类游戏，这就是我的全部
in data centers so that people can play
these kind of games and that's all I
必须说关于农场的问题，如果有人有，如果没有，很高兴提出任何疑问
have to say about farm happy to take any
questions if anybody has some and if not
下周我会再见到你，也许你很高兴知道
I'll see you next week with a spark
which is you may be happy to know
绝对不是我听到大家再见的交易
absolutely not about transactions I
heard everyone bye-bye
[音乐]
[Music]